They think they control him. Think again.
Red Scorpion is a adventure, action, war film directed by Joseph Zito.
A Soviet commando is sent to eliminate a rebel leader in Africa.
Soon he finds himself doubting his mission and his loyalty.
Lt. Nikolai Rachenko, played by Dolph Lundgren.
Dewey Ferguson, played by M. Emmet Walsh.
Kallunda Kintash, played by Al White.
General Vortek, played by T. P. McKenna.
Colonel Zayas, played by Carmen Argenziano.
Sgt. Mendez, played by Alex Colon.
Red Scorpion is a 1988 American action film starring
Dolph Lundgren and directed by Joseph Zito.
Lundgren appears as a Soviet special forces ("Spetsnaz") operative sent to assassinate
an anti-communist rebel leader in Africa, only to side with the rebels.
It was produced by lobbyist Jack Abramoff and controversially filmed in South West
Africa with the support of the apartheid-era South African government.
The film was released in the United States on April 21, 1989.
It is the first installment in the Red Scorpion film series.
The film explores themes of cold war, traitor,
mission of murder, uprising, revenge.